Garrett Heiner - Software Engineer

t: 480.747.7878 e: garrett.heiner@gmail.com Phoenix, AZ <u>Linkedin</u> <u>GitHub</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

Summary

I am a driven and resilient individual with experience in sales and service positions that have honed my leadership, communication, and problem-solving skills. My diverse background in trades & finance has prepared me to bring ideas to life through my passion for learning and producing quality work. With a focus on web development, I am ready to create efficient and effective solutions for any project.

Skills

Python, Django, JavaScript, Node, React, Next, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby, Express, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Heroku, Netlify, Vercel, Git, CLI, Agile

Projects

SimuStock - A simulation trading application for stocks github

Python, Django, PostgreSQL, React, JavaScript, BeautifulSoup

- Developed a mobile-oriented trading simulation application using BeautifulSoup for near-real-time stock data scraping, offering users a risk-free trading environment
- Integrated full user functionality, including account management, trading operations, and social features like viewing and interacting with friends' portfolios and trades

Card.io - A digital flashcard creation & study app live site | github

JavaScript , Express , MongoDB , Node.js , Cloudinary API

- Constructed a full-stack MERN application to allow users to generate, revise, remove and study digital flashcards
- Employed the Cloudinary API for handling image uploads, storage, and retrieval for user's flashcards

Everyone's a Critic - A movie centered social media app live site | github

JavaScript, Express, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Heroku

- Implemented Bootstrap framework to make an interactive and responsive UX
- Built a full-stack application using Node.js with Express and PostgreSQL, creating fully functioning CRUD features for users, favorites lists, movie reviews and comments.

The Bridge Troll's Toll - A multiple choice quiz game live site | github

HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3

- Leveraged JavaScript DOM manipulation to render client-side cards on a single web page
- Utilized responsive CSS to provide an enjoyable desktop or mobile user experience

Experience

Student, General Assembly | Spring 2023 | Remote

500+ hour Immersive Software Engineering course with focus on full stack web development

Mortgage Loan Originator, American Pacific Mortgage | October 2021 - February 2023

- Expertly managed challenging loan scenarios, consistently securing loan approvals for clients with complex financial profiles
- Established and nurtured relationships with new brokers, expanding access to specialty loan programs and enhancing overall customer satisfaction and feedback

Video Ingest Technician, iMemories | October 2019 - October 2021

- Efficiently processed and ingested 1,000+ hours of video content per month, ensuring 99% accuracy and quality
- Collaborated in the development of an updated video ingest workflow, reducing processing time and increasing production output by 30%

Pest Control Sales & Service, Apex Environmental | May 2016 - September 2019

- Regularly surpassed sales goals, playing a key role in expanding the company's customer base and market share
- Provided exceptional customer service and pest control solutions, resulting in a 95% customer retention rate and numerous client referrals

Education

Brigham Young University | 2015 - 2016 | Rexburg, ID Credits towards Bachelor of Science Degree in Business Finance